YOUSSEF EL-HROUZI

Front-End Developer

CONTACT

Website: https://el-hrouzi.com Phone: +212 (0)663 020 777 Email: youssef.el.hrouzi@gmail.com Address: Sidi Slimane, Morocco Linked-in: linkedin.com/in/el-hrouzi Skype: live:youssimail

CERTIFICATIONS

• Meta Front-End Developer:

By Meta on Coursera – 07/2023 Certificate's ID: 4CZZMLE3TTKX

RELEVANT SKILLS

1. Technical skills:

- HTML5, CSS3
- Sass, Tailwind, Bootstrap
- React, JavaScript/ES6+, Jest
- Figma, Git, GitHub
- Sanity CMS
- Data Structures & Algorithms

2. Soft skills:

- Time management
- Working under pressure
- Quick adaptation to new tasks
- Teamwork
- Interpersonnel Communication

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Every job role needs technical and soft skills, my dedication to continuous learning and self-improvement in web development, along with the various real-life projects I developed with passion, showcase my technical skills.

Although my current and prior job roles are not directly related to the development field, they have provided me with a strong foundation of soft skills, which, combined with my technical expertise, undoubtedly make me confident to excel in any entry-level Front-end developer role.

MAIN PROJECTS (3 of 10+ projects)

My Personal Portfolio (https://el-hrouzi.com)

Developed a React-based SPA showcasing my front-end development skills, projects, certificates, and personality. The portfolio utilizes Sanity as a backend Content Management System and includes a contact form for potential clients or recruiters.

Main features:

- Interactive Sections: Implemented a visually appealing and user-friendly layout with dedicated sections for: "About, Work, Skills & Certifications, Testimonials, Contact".
- Integrated a Sanity system for the application's content management.
- Implemented a filtering system to allow users to easily browse projects based on technology.
- Integrated Framer Motion animations to enhance the user experience and create a more dynamic and visually appealing presentation.
- Implemented a fully responsive design, ensuring a seamless user experience across different devices.

My role in the app:

- Developed the entire front-end of the application using React.
- Created a responsive and visually appealing user interface using Tailwind CSS, custom animations and transitions for a more engaging user experience.
- Connected the UI to Sanity (including schema design, content management and data fetching).
- Successfully deployed the portfolio to a hosting service.

Used technologies:

• React, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Sanity, Framer Motion

Little Lemon Restaurant (https://my-little-lemon.onrender.com)

Developed a single-page web application serving as a restaurant website template. This project, an enhanced version of the Meta Capstone, focused on building a front-end React application from scratch.

Main features:

- Implemented an online table reservation system with a multi-step form.
- Displayed restaurant menu details and available meals.
- Enabled online ordering for pickup or delivery, including checkout processing.
- Created a feedback form to encourage user engagement and gather valuable insights.
- Featured user testimonials to showcase customer experiences.
- Implemented robust form validation to ensure accurate data input, reduce data entry errors and enhance user experience.
- Implemented a fully responsive design, adapting to different screen sizes.

EDUCATION

- Specialized Technician Diploma 09/2000 - 06/2002 - Specialized Institute of Applied Technology, Kenitra-Morocco
 - o Information systems analysis
- Conceptual modeling and databases.
- Applications development
- University Certificate of Scientific
 Studies physics and Chemistry
 09/1997 07/2000
 Ibn Tofail University, Kenitra- Morocco

LANGUAGES

- Arabic Mother language
- French B2
- English B1

My role in the app:

- Designed and styled a responsive user interface (UI).
- Developed the website's front-end using React.
- Implemented unit tests using Jest.
- Deployed the application to a hosting service.

Used technologies:

• Figma, HTML, CSS-modules, React, JavaScript, Jest

> Salaty - Prayer Times (https://salaty.onrender.com)

Developed a single-page web application designed to help Muslims stay punctual with their daily prayers. Salaty - Prayer Times provides a range of features and services to enhance their prayer experience.

Main features:

- Implemented a feature to display accurate prayer times for the five daily prayers based on the user's current location or a chosen city. This includes:
 - o Dynamic Location Detection: Integrated geolocation services.
 - o City Selection: Implemented an auto-complete feature to allow users to easily search and select a city.
- Displayed a user-friendly Islamic/Lunar calendar based on specific API.
- Created a feature that shows the next prayer with its remaining start time.
- Integrated Google Maps to display nearby mosques based on user's location.
- Implemented an audio and visual notification system to play the Athan (call to prayer) at the appropriate times.
- Created a settings panel to allow users to customize their preferences.

My role in the app:

- Designed and implemented the user interface (UI).
- Developed the front-end of the application.
- Connected the application to external APIs to retrieve prayer times, geolocation data, and other relevant information.
- Built the back-end infrastructure using Node.js and Express.
- Deployed the application to a hosting service.

Used technologies:

• HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Figma, Git

WORK HISTORY

HR records manager - Since 11/2019

Provincial Directorate of the Ministry of Education, Sidi Slimane-Maroc

- Manage the HR' archives service of the education sector in the province.
- Ensuring the preservation of the integrity of documents and archival funds relating to the careers of education personnel.

School administrative office manager - 03/2018 - 11/2019

Allal El Fassi Secondary School, Sidi Slimane-Morocco

- Monitor the educational and disciplinary situations of more than 300 students.
- Manage the students' school records and produce documents related to their enrolment.

Laboratory technician - 09/2010 - 03/2018

Allal El Fassi Secondary School, Sidi Slimane-Morocco

- Conduct and prepare experiments related to the scientific and practical work of the secondary classes.
- Manage the school laboratory with dedicated documents and software.